<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EcoQuants</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on EcoQuants</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Except where otherwise noted, content is under &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC License&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Project setup for reproducible research</title>
      <link>/2017/02/project-setup-for-reproducible-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/project-setup-for-reproducible-research/</guid>
      <description> In Github, setup issues, milestones, project. Eg nrel-cables:
 #10: setup Github site w/ issues, milestones and project #11: setup Rmarkdown doc w/ Zotero refs to output: pdf, docx, html  …more on this later…
 Kanban style setup  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check Water Quality</title>
      <link>/app/wqck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 20:47:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/app/wqck/</guid>
      <description>This idea was initiated by environmental attorney Jesse Swanhuyser, who sought to make it easier for potential point source pollutors to comply with California state water quality monitoring requirements, including 4 samples over the 6 month rainy season. The first major rain is the most important to capture, and subsequent sampling is ideally spaced out in time.
We&amp;rsquo;re developing a subscription and notification system such that 10-day precipitation forecasts are analyzed based on site-specific climatologies and reporting histories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environmental DNA</title>
      <link>/app/edna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 20:47:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/app/edna/</guid>
      <description>The eDNA Explorer enables exploration in time, space and taxa.
Client: Marine Biodiversity Observaion Network, NOAA National Marine Sanctuaries</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Infographic</title>
      <link>/app/infographic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 20:47:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/app/infographic/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocean Health Index</title>
      <link>/app/ohi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 20:47:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/app/ohi/</guid>
      <description>The Ocean Health Index is a complex framework with many goals, dimensions and layers. This application helps users visualize the many levels of information as maps, flower plots, time series and tables.
 Application to explore the Ocean Health Index here with mouse over the United States, revealing the country&amp;rsquo;s flower plot and overall score in the upper right.
For more on the Ocean Health Index, please visit:
 OHI-science.org: open data science tools and resources OceanHealthIndex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Route Ships to Avoid Whale Strike</title>
      <link>/app/routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 20:47:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/app/routing/</guid>
      <description>Routes between starting and end points are selectable from the drop-down selections as ports and major entry points to British Columbia, or arbitrary start and end points can be entered. Routes are then visible in the interactive map based on varying levels of avoidance of marine mammal hotspots as derived by summing across marine mammal density surfaces and weighting by conservation concern. This uses a prescriptive least-cost routing approach rather than post-hoc evaluation of proposed routes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Offshore Wind Energy Development</title>
      <link>/app/siting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 20:47:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/app/siting/</guid>
      <description>Siting offshore wind energy development to minimize impacts on birds in space and whales in time 
Sites on the map (10 km2 pixels) in the US Mid-Atlantic are colored according to the average utility depicted in the tradeoff plot to: maximize profitability to offshore wind energy development (net present value in US$, on normalized scale) on y-axis, and minimizing bird sensitivity on x-axis (based on 20 bird species distributions summed and weighted by sensitivity to collision and displacement, also on a normalized scale).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EcoQuants website launched with free hosting and interactive visualizations</title>
      <link>/2017/02/ecoquants-website-launched-with-free-hosting-and-interactive-visualizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/ecoquants-website-launched-with-free-hosting-and-interactive-visualizations/</guid>
      <description>The website EcoQuants is alive and ticking! Here’s what I’m using in order to host it for free and still contain dynamic content:
 Github Pages: hosting for free, and files versioned using git blogdown: R package to use the fast Hugo templating engine hugo-theme-bootstrap4-blog: latest Bootstrap applied to Hugo template boostrap4-carousel: baked this into the index page  htmlwidgets Power of d3 JS ported to single R functions to provide interactive experience from static web files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>At EcoQuants, we see the world as a complex place. Management of our natural resources and sustainable human uses require a data driven approach.
Philosophy  The EcoQuants logo is fashioned around the ensō, a symbol in Zen calligraphy representing the striving towards unity (a circle) and embrace of imperfection (incomplete circle). At EcoQuants we similarly seek to model complex systems in a holistic manner, and still work with inevitable uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis</title>
      <link>/service/analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/service/analysis/</guid>
      <description>We are fans of the data science process as outlined by Hadley Wickham in R for Data Science:
Usually most of the work in modeling is at the data preparation and interpretation stages, ie before and after modeling. I&amp;rsquo;m an advocate of efficient data ingestion (estimated 50-80%spent on collection and preparation of data), the iterative process of exploratory data analysis and closing the gap between the starting with a question and sharing analytical results online and interactively to any audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development</title>
      <link>/service/development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/service/development/</guid>
      <description>We rapidly develop interactive data driven web applications, particularly those with complexity in space, time and taxa. We employ technologies such as Shiny &amp;reg; and Jupyter (Python), as well as Google App and Earth Engines. We can facilitate hosting these applications in the cloud, and scale resources as needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/</guid>
      <description>Active Biodiversity Synthesis and Visualization &amp;ndash; Marine Biodiversity Observation Network (MBON) The Marine Biodiversity Observation Network (MBON) is applying cutting edge observation techniques, such as environmental DNA (eDNA) and seascape analysis, to monitor life in the sea.
Sponsors: NASA, NOAA
Submarine Cable Conflict Analysis with Marine Renewables &amp;ndash; National Renewable Energy Labs (NREL) Sponsors: NREL
Historical Visualization &amp;ndash; Ocean Health Index (OHI) Sponsors: Conservation International, National Center for Analaysis &amp;amp; Synthesis</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training</title>
      <link>/service/training/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/service/training/</guid>
      <description>We teach at the intersection of spatial analysis, ecology and data science.
Courses  Instructor for Geographic Information Systems (GIS) at UCSB, Spring 2016 Instructor for Environmental Informatics at UCSB, Winter 2016 Instructor for Advanced Topics in GIS at UCSB, Fall 2014+2015 Instructor for Landscape Ecology at UCSB, Winter 2015 Instructor for Marine Geospatial Analysis at Duke, Spring 2012 Lab Instructor for Conservation Planning at UCSB, Winter 2011 Teaching Assistant for Advanced Geospatial Analysis at Duke, Fall 2010 Teaching Assistant for Marine Geospatial Analysis at Duke, Spring 2009  Workshops.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>