<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tag2 on EcoQuants</title>
    <link>/tags/tag2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tag2 on EcoQuants</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Except where otherwise noted, content is under &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC License&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 20:47:58 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/tag2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Check Water Quality</title>
      <link>/app/wqck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 20:47:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/app/wqck/</guid>
      <description>This idea was initiated by environmental attorney Jesse Swanhuyser, who sought to make it easier for potential point source pollutors to comply with California state water quality monitoring requirements, including 4 samples over the 6 month rainy season. The first major rain is the most important to capture, and subsequent sampling is ideally spaced out in time.
We&amp;rsquo;re developing a subscription and notification system such that 10-day precipitation forecasts are analyzed based on site-specific climatologies and reporting histories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environmental DNA</title>
      <link>/app/edna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 20:47:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/app/edna/</guid>
      <description>The eDNA Explorer enables exploration in time, space and taxa.
Client: Marine Biodiversity Observaion Network, NOAA National Marine Sanctuaries</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Infographic</title>
      <link>/app/infographic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 20:47:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/app/infographic/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocean Health Index</title>
      <link>/app/ohi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 20:47:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/app/ohi/</guid>
      <description>The Ocean Health Index is a complex framework with many goals, dimensions and layers. This application helps users visualize the many levels of information as maps, flower plots, time series and tables.
 Application to explore the Ocean Health Index here with mouse over the United States, revealing the country&amp;rsquo;s flower plot and overall score in the upper right.
For more on the Ocean Health Index, please visit:
 OHI-science.org: open data science tools and resources OceanHealthIndex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Route Ships to Avoid Whale Strike</title>
      <link>/app/routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 20:47:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/app/routing/</guid>
      <description>Routes between starting and end points are selectable from the drop-down selections as ports and major entry points to British Columbia, or arbitrary start and end points can be entered. Routes are then visible in the interactive map based on varying levels of avoidance of marine mammal hotspots as derived by summing across marine mammal density surfaces and weighting by conservation concern. This uses a prescriptive least-cost routing approach rather than post-hoc evaluation of proposed routes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Offshore Wind Energy Development</title>
      <link>/app/siting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 20:47:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/app/siting/</guid>
      <description>Siting offshore wind energy development to minimize impacts on birds in space and whales in time 
Sites on the map (10 km2 pixels) in the US Mid-Atlantic are colored according to the average utility depicted in the tradeoff plot to: maximize profitability to offshore wind energy development (net present value in US$, on normalized scale) on y-axis, and minimizing bird sensitivity on x-axis (based on 20 bird species distributions summed and weighted by sensitivity to collision and displacement, also on a normalized scale).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
